

Josh ShoneFull-stack developer

(a) josh.shone@gmail.com

+49 1765 793 7870

Perlin

ioshshone.com

Hi, I'm Josh - a full-stack developer living in Berlin (originally from Canberra, Australia). I've worked as a developer for almost 10 years, with a broad range of experience from web development and native apps, to backend and system languages like C++ and Go. I'm also a long-time linux and open-source enthusiast.

Employment

flowkey GmbH

© Berlin 2019 - 2020
4 months

I worked briefly at flowkey GmbH, completing several projects for their piano learning web-app such as the implementation of their 'Netflix' style redesign and a specialized layout algorithm for note name internationalization. A variety of tools and technologies were covered, such as GraphQL/Apollo, React, MongoDB, Swift and Android debugging.

KIWI.KI GmbH

© Berlin 2016 - 2018 2 years, 6 months

Developed and released an overhauled version of KIWI's web-based portal for housing companies, covering back-end work (Python, Flask), database refactoring (PostgreSQL), front-end design and implementation (ES6 Javascript, Backbone, Foundation CSS), build system re-tooling (NodeJS, Gulp), and deployment (Kubernetes).

My work at KIWI was often truely full-stack, with tasks requiring me to flash hardware to test new firmware, delve into dense SQL queries, all the way up to UI-design and user-experience considerations; even some graphic-design.

General Dynamics Mediaware

Q Canberra 2012 - 2015

3 years, 4 months

Initial role as C++ programmer engaged in performance analysis, debugging and feature development on a large codebase. Worked in a mid-sized Agile team adhering to well-defined processes for issue-tracking, continuous integration, customer feedback and development iterations. I helped develop the company's flagship product InStream, a high-performance multi-threaded video processing service for broadcast television.

Took on a new role as primary web developer after showing initiative by producing browser-based performance analysis tooling. Went on to develop a company-wide framework for service control utilizing websocket-based RPC (WAMP) and reactor-based networking (Twisted). Was also responsible for UI design, mockups, user-testing and producing high-quality documentation.

NCH Software

Canberra

2009 - 2012 3 years, 4 months

Was responsible for creating several native desktop applications from scratch, including a non-destructive photo editor and musical notation software. Initial concept, design, mockups, prototyping, development and release was handled either solo or in small teams. Highlights:

- · Designed a unique modeless editing UI for sheet music.
- Implemented a dynamic level-of-detail system for smoothly scaling fast fourier transform visualizations.
- Developed a high-performance non-destructive image transformation and layering system.

Education

Academy of Interactive Entertainment

ରେ Adv. Diploma of Professional Game Development

Cert IV in 3D Animation for Games and Film

CH COLLIN OF AMERICAN FOR CAMPOS AND A MINI

Covered a broad range of computer science and visual design topics, including:

- Realtime games programming in C++ (Visual Studio)
- Composition, layout and prototyping
- 3D content creation and animation (3dsMax)
- Use of realtime graphics engines (Unreal)

Deutsche Akademie für Sprachen

2007 - 2008

Canberra

ରେ A2 level German

I have decided to take a break from full-time software development and am currently taking advantage of a language-learning visa to learn German which will help with my goal of acheiving permanent residency in Germany.

Skills

HTML

Over 5 years professional experience with modern web standards, client-side rendering, responsive design etc. Some topics delved into, both professionally and personally:

- · WebRTC/Websockets
- · Advanced Canvas and SVG based animation
- Various SPA techniques and use of Service Workers

Node.is

Node and its build tooling and package ecosystem has been a mainstay for many projects and products I've worked on.

Python

Gained a deep knowledge after using Python professionally for many years in server-side networking. I have experience developing, maintaining and deploying Python-based APIs and applications.

C++

Long and deeply involved history with C++ professionally, in personal projects and while studying games programming. Strong OOP design, multi-threaded/high-performance disciplines, advanced use of language features.

Gc

I am familiar with Go and use it in personal projects. I'm looking forward to using it professionally.

Linux

Linux has been my preferred development environment for most of my career, and I greatly value the speed and simplicity of an installation that I have personally customized.

Javascript

Experience with developing large, well structured JS codebases in a variety of frameworks, with ES6/ES7 language features and an emphasis on writing clean, functional-style code.

My coding style and priorities when writing Javascript come from a background in statically-typed languages, which I feel helps me write testable and reliable codebases.

CSS

I extract a perverse pleasure from debugging puzzling layout glitches and implementing designs that thoroughly cover every edge-case.

I have experience with pre-processors like SASS and LESS, and both developing styling with modern CSS3 and highly cross-browser compatible stylesheets.

Kubernetes

I have experience working in an entirely Kubernetes-based development pipeline, where I have helped deploy and manage pre-production and staging environments.

SQL

I have experience writing SQL-backed server code and applications with async/non-blocking and high-performance queries. I've been responsible for large-scale database refactoring, performance analysis and customer data anonymization.

Git

Used extensively both professionally and personally. Have a solid understanding of underlying concepts, and use it for the swiss-army-knife toolkit it is.